Guide to the Harry Ogden Collection PR 147
New-York Historical Society
Harry Ogden collection
18xx-19xx
New-York Historical Society
PR 147
0.01 Linear feet in....
- Illustrations from Uniform of the Army of the United States by H.A. Ogden (1774-1858), 1885 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Illustrations from Uniform of the Army of the United States by H.A. Ogden (1858 - 1888), 1885 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Illustrations from Uniform of the Army of the United States, Volume II, by H. A. Ogden (1898 - 1907), 1901, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Glossy Prints of H.A. Ogden Paintings, 1932, 1935, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Illustrations by H.A. Ogden (non-military), 1874 - 1889, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Some Ogden illustrations from Harper's, Harper's Weekly, Le Monde, Life, Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper
- State Militia, Cadets and Miscellaneous Military, 1895, 1898, 1899, 1904, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Includes a book, A Vision of War by Col. Robert G. Ingersoll, illustrated by H.A. Ogden (1899). Some colored illustrations are for The Sunday Herald in 1895. Illustrations for Harper's Weekly.
- Illustrations U.S. Army (1800 - 1865), 1905, 1912, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Some of the illustrations are marked on the back, "Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923"
- Illustrations - Revolutionary War by H.A. Ogden, 1883, 1898, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Some of the illustrations are marked on the back, "Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923". Includes two Harper's Weekly of 1883 and 1898 with illustrations by H.A. Ogden.
- Illustrations of U.S. Army from 1866 to World War I by H.A. Ogden, 1874 -1917, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Some of the illustrations are marked on the back, "Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923". Includes pages from Harper's Weekly, New York Home Life, Life, Vanity Fair, Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper with illustrations by H.A. Ogden.
- Civil War Illustrations, Folders 1 - 3, 1862 - 1922 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  Some of the illustrations are marked on the back, "Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923". Illustrations from Harper's Weekly and other newspapers of Civil War generals, battles, monuments - not done by H.A. Ogden.
- Illustrations of the Navy, 1885 - 1924 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Includes a First National Movie Booklet for the 1924 movie, the Sea Hawk, a 1918 Booklet, Our Defenders. Clippings with ships, naval uniforms - not illustrated by H.A. Ogden.
- Illustrations of the Revolutionary War, 1931, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Includes clipped illustrations not by H.A. Ogden.
- Illustrations of U.S. Army, 1900 - pre WWI, 1899 - 1914 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Includes photographic clippings of army, calvary.
- Illustrations of US Army, 1866 -1897, 1874 - 1902 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Many of the clipped illustrations are from Harper's Weekly. The illustrations are not done by H.A. Ogden.
- Illustrations of Miscellaneous U.S. Military, 1800 - 1860, 1866 - 1900 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Some of the illustrations are marked on the back, "Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923". Many clippings are from Harper's Weekly, not done by H.A. Ogden.
- Illustrations of Boxer Rebellion, 1900, 1900 - 1901 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Includes photographic images of the Boxer Rebellion
- Illustrations of World War I, 1915 -1919 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Includes a small U.S. Marine recruiting booklet, a sheet of stamps with Army officers in different dress.
- Spanish American War, 1898 - 1915 (Box 4, Folder 1-11)
  Includes 11 folders of newspaper clippings (Leslie's Weekly, Leslie's Popular Monthly, Mail and Express Illustrated, New York Times, Harper's Weekly, Collier's Weekly, Navy and Army Illustrated, Munsey Magazine, Scribner's Magazine, McClure's Magazine, Metropolitan Magazine, The Commercial Advertiser) of uniforms worn around the time of Spanish American War. Includes series of newspaper photographs from Camp Black in Hempstead, New York. Includes newspaper photographs of Land and Water Parades of the Dewey Celebration in 1899. Includes newspaper photographs and drawings of Dewey celebrations at the Capitol and in Boston. Includes a lithograph of U.S. Navy Shells (in actual size) by the The Strobridge Litho. Co. of Cincinnati. Includes Army and Navy Register article of July 19, 1902 describing uniforms of the United States Army. Includes lithograph of 1898 titled "The North Atlantic Squadron and Torpedo Flotilla at Sea". Includes newspaper photographs of The Rough Riders. Includes articles by Theodore Roosevelt on The Rough Riders.
- British Uniforms - Zulu War and Indian Revolution, 1879 -1904 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Includes newspaper clippings focused on British uniforms in War of Sudan, War in Egypt, Zulu War, Afghan War, and Indian Revolution.
- British Uniforms (Folders 2-5), 1885 - 1918 (Box 5, Folder 2-5)
  Includes 4 folders of newspaper clippings (and 4 books) reflecting different British military uniforms. Includes a print of Ogden's work. Includes pieces from the Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923 (Cut-outs of British Soliders pasted on cardboard). Includes Following the Drum, published in London by William Allen & Co. Includes British Soldiers, Past and Present - 1794-1894, by R. Simkin, published by Frederick Warne & Co. London (2 copies0. Includes Soldiers of the Century by R. Simkin, published by Dean & Son, Limited, London.
- British Uniforms - Boer War, 1875-1901 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Includes newspaper clippings focused on British uniforms in the Boer War.
- British Uniforms, 1884 -1924 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  Includes 4 folders of newspaper and other clippings focused on English uniforms, including Gurkha soldiers' uniforms, Scottish Highland regiments, Bengal Army uniforms. Includes loose pages from Follow the Drum. Includes a foldout describing the order of the troops for Queen Victoria's Diamond Jubilee. Includes loose book pages from Charles M. Lefferts Collection 1923 (Some from Soldiers of a Century by R. Simkin). Includes pamphlet from Historical Pageant, Philadelphia, October 7-12, 1912. Includes program book for The Militray Tournament: Direct from London, England at Madison Square Garden, 1893. Includes 1888 photographic prints (?) of dressed soldiers. Includes series of prints entitled, Types of the British Army and Navy.
- French Uniforms, German Uniforms, Russo-Japanese War - French Uniforms (Folders 1-3), 1870 - 1916 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  Includes 3 separate folders. Includes newspaper and other clippings depicting french uniforms throughout history. Includes pencil sketches. Includes items from Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923. Includes small illustrated books, Cahiers D'Enseignement Illustres and Les Sapeurs-Pompiers. Includes photographs of Meissonier's Napoleon Paintings.
- French Uniforms, German Uniforms, Russo-Japanese War - German Uniforms, 1885 - 1914 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings depicting german uniforms throughout history. Includes several prints.
- French Uniforms, German Uniforms, Russo-Japanes War - Russo-Japanese War, 1878 - 1905 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings depicting uniforms of the Russians and Japanese. Includes items from Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923. Includes a small book, Die Russische Armee.
- Medieval: Warfare, Arms, Personalities, Manner and Customs, Stage, Pageants, Costumes, Trades and Occupations - Manners/Customs, 1879 - 1924 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings reflecting manners of Medieval dress. Includes two small books, Tom Pouce and Barbe Bleue, published in Paris by Maison Quantin.
- Medieval: Warfare, Arms, Personalities, Manner and Customs, Stage, Pageants, Costumes, Trades and Occupations - Personalities, 1885 - 1911 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings focused on the medieval dress of individuals, such as Kings, Queens, etc.
- Medieval: Warfare, Arms, Personalities, Manner and Customs, Stage, Pageants, Costumes, Trades and Occupations - Arms and Armor, 1879 - 1924 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings depicting Medieval arms and armor. Includes Spanish postcards showing arms and armor. Includes photograph of men in armor by E. Ziegler, Paris, and other photographs. Includes Metropolitan Museum of Art reprint of article, On American Polearms, Especially Those in The Metropolitan Museum of Art by Bashford Dean.
- Medieval: Warfare, Arms, Personalities, Manner and Customs, Stage, Pageants, Costumes, Trades and Occupations - Warfare, 1890 - 1914 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings depicting Medieval warfare. Includes some prints.
- Medieval: Warfare, Arms, Personalities, Manner and Customs, Stage, Pageants, Costumes, Trades and Occupations - Stage, 1898 - 1925 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings about Medieval stage productions, including The Harlequin King, The Tyrant, Rose Marie, Joan of Arc, The Cardinal, The Gondoliers, Ulysses, Much Ado about Nothing, The Swashbuckler, King Richard II, The Twin Sister, Paolo and Francesca, The Beauty Stone, The Pirates of Penzance, In Days of Old, King John, Lohengrin, The Two Pins, Pelleas et Melisande, and The Tempter.
- Medieval: Warfare, Arms, Personalities, Manner and Customs, Stage, Pageants, Costumes, Trades and Occupations - Pageants, 1891 - 1924 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Includes several program booklets from Pageants, including Bury St. Edmunds (Philadelphia, 07/8-13/1907), The Book of the Pageant (Philadelphia, 10/09/1908), May Day Revels and Plays (Bryn Mawr, 05/9-10/1924). Includes newspaper clippings from pageants at St. Albans, Chelsea, Fulham, Winchester, Colchester, Deans Yard, and London.
- Medieval: Warfare, Arms, Personalities, Manner and Customs, Stage, Pageants, Costumes, Trades and Occupations - Costumes, 1877 - 1924 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings of medieval costumes. Includes items from the Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923.
- Medieval: Warfare, Arms, Personalities, Manner and Customs, Stage, Pageants, Costumes, Trades and Occupations - Trades and Occupations, 1896 - 1921 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings of medieval trades.
- Insignia and Accessories, Guns and Artillery, Forts and Armories, Native Americans and the West, Balkan Wars, Greek and Roman Costume, Misc. - Insignia and Accessories, 1884 - 1922 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings of insignia and accessories, including hats, flags, metals, swords, etc. Includes items from the Charles M. Lefferts Collection 1923. Includes a few prints.
- Insignia and Accessories, Guns and Artillery, Forts and Armories, Native Americans and the West, Balkan Wars, Greek and Roman Costume, Misc. - Guns and Artillery, 1889 - 1914 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings of guns and artillery.
- Insignia and Accessories, Guns and Artillery, Forts and Armories, Native Americans and the West, Balkan Wars, Greek and Roman Costume, Misc. - Forts and Armories, 1880 - 1901, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings of forts and armories, including The White House, The Alamo, Brooklyn Armory, Park Avenue Armory, The 7th Regiment Armory (New York), Chicago Armory, Oklahoma barracks.
- Insignia and Accessories, Guns and Artillery, Forts and Armories, Native Americans and the West, Balkan Wars, Greek and Roman Costume, Misc. - State Militia and National Guardsmen, 1871 - 1928 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings showing different state regiments, many are from New York and Massachusetts. Includes items from the Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923.
- Insignia and Accessories, Guns and Artillery, Forts and Armories, Native Americans and the West, Balkan Wars, Greek and Roman Costume, Misc. - Native Americans and the West, Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Includes mainly prints of cowboys and Native Americans, some clippings. Most, if not all, items appear to be from the Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923.
- Insignia and Accessories, Guns and Artillery, Forts and Armories, Native Americans and the West, Balkan Wars, Greek and Roman Costume, Misc. - Balkan Wars, 1877 - 1896 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings depicting military uniforms from the Balkan Wars.
- Insignia and Accessories, Guns and Artillery, Forts and Armories, Native Americans and the West, Balkan Wars, Greek and Roman Costume, Misc. - Greek and Roman Costume, 1886 - 1925 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings depicting Greek and Roman costume. No items are stamped - The Harry A. Ogden Collection - 1936.
- Insignia and Accessories, Guns and Artillery, Forts and Armories, Native Americans and the West, Balkan Wars, Greek and Roman Costume, Misc. - Spiritual/Religion, 1878 - 1925 (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings of religious subjects, including Jesus Christ, the Apostles, Saints, Angels. Includes book of prints, Meisterwerfe der Chrimlichen Kunm. No item is stamped Harry A. Ogden Collection - 1936.
- Insignia and Accessories, Guns and Artillery, Forts and Armories, Native Americans and the West, Balkan Wars, Greek and Roman Costume, Misc. - Dogs, 1880 - 1914 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Includes newspaper and other clippings of pictures of different breeds of dogs. No item is stamped Harry A. Ogden Collection - 1936.
- Insignia and Accessories, Guns and Artillery, Forts and Armories, Native Americans and the West, Balkan Wars, Greek and Roman Costume, Misc. - Miscellaneous, 1878 - 1916 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Includes miscellaneous material and clippings depicting different military uniforms from around the world and from different historic eras. Includes items from the Charles M. Lefferts Collection - 1923. Includes pages from Armed Europe, published by Raphael Tuck and Sons.